Guide to the Margaret Croyden Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- December 2015 Acquistion, 1922-2013; 11.18 linear feet (18 boxes) + 1 broadside
  - Writings and Publications, 1975-2011; Series I; 1.25 linear feet (3 boxes)
    - The Years in Between
      - Correspondence and notes, 2006–2008 (Box 18)
      - X Libris documents, 2010 (Box 18)
      - X Libris documents and computer printout draft, 2011 (Box 18)
      - Draft, typescript copy, undated (Box 18)
      - Draft, typescript copy, undated (Box 18)
        Also contains pages from an unidentified manuscript.
      - Manuscript, typescript copy, annotated, pages 1-100, undated (Box 18)
      - Manuscript, typescript copy, annotated, pages 101-200, undated (Box 18)
      - Manuscript, typescript copy, annotated pages 201-271, afterword and miscelleanous pages, undated (Box 19)
      - Manuscript, typescript copy, miscelleanous pages, undated (Box 19)
    - Research plans for book about Peter Brook's life, undated (Box 19)
    - Conversations with Peter Brook publication party invitations, royalties, and flyers for other works, 2006; undated (Box 19)
    - Farewell Mr. Hemingway
      - Printout draft copy, undated (Box 19)
      - Printout draft copy, Parts I-III, undated (Box 19)
      - Printout draft copy, Parts IV- V, undated (Box 19)
      - Printout draft copy, Parts VI- VIII, undated (Box 19)
      - Notes and clippings, undated
    - Untitled manuscript draft, typescript copy, Chapters 3-6, undated (Box 19)
    - Untitled manuscript draft, typescript copy, pages 174- 284, undated (Box 19)
    - Untitled manuscript draft, typescript copy, pages 285- 365, undated (Box 19)
    - The Winter of Our Desire correspondence with publishers and literary agents, 1993–2003 (Box 20)
    - The Romantics poetry and writings, undated (Box 20)
    - Miscelleanous book related documents, 2000 (Box 20)
  - Personal Papers, 1922-2013; Series II
    Series II is arranged in loose groupings by format as recieved by the library.
    Series II includes Croyden's personal diaries, planners, and correspondence. Also included are documents pertaining to her name change and the deaths of her sister and father.
    - Birth certificate: original and copy, 1922–1987 (Box 20)
    - Diary, 1941–1945 (Box 20)
    - Diary ("Patients Valuables: Part II"), 1946 (Box 20)
    - Diary, 1947–1950 (Box 20)
    - Diary entry, 1953 September (Box 20)
    - Diary entry, 1960 February (Box 20)
    - Diary, 1983–1990 (Box 20)
    - Correspondence (note: with typed manuscript writing on one letter), 1949 (Box 20)
    - Name change documentation, 1957 (Box 20)
    - Daily Planner, 2001 (Box 20)
    - Daily Planner, 2002 (Box 20)
    - Daily Planner, 2004 (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous personal documents, 1994–2013 (Box 20)
    - Blank notebook with handwritten inscription, 1997 (Box 20)
    - Sylvia Rosenberg documents and father's death certificate, 1993–2005 (Box 20)
    - Computer instructions, 1999–2003 (Box 20)
    - Stanton book club email list, 2012 (Box 21)
    - Glasses case with address, undated (Box 21)
  - Theater Publications and Related Materials, 1969-2013; Series III; 1.25 linear feet (3 boxes)
    Series III is arranged in loose groupings by format as recieved by the library.
    Series III contains theater reviews and other materials related to Croyden's career as a theater critic. Included are reviews posted in "Croyden's Corner" in the New York Theater Wire. Also included are issues of Theater Week and American Theatre, which published Croyden's reviews. One issue of AI: Performance for the Planet is also included. Other files pertain to Croyden's study of Jerzy Grotowski, Peter Brook, and other theater luminaries.
    - Theater reviews, 1969–1970 (Box 21)
    - Theater reviews, 1971–1976 (Box 21)
    - Theater reviews, 1977–1981 (Box 21)
    - Theater reviews, 1982–1984 (Box 21)
    - Theater reviews, 1985–1986 (Box 21)
    - Theater reviews, 1987–1990 (Box 21)
    - Theater reviews, 1993–2000 (Box 21)
    - International theater articles, 1974–2000 (Box 21)
    - Undated theater articles (Box 21)
    - Croyden's Corner, New York Theater Wire, 1997–1998 (Box 21)
    - Croyden's Corner, New York Theater Wire, 1999–2000 (Box 21)
    - Croyden's Corner, New York Theater Wire, 2001–2002 (Box 21)
    - Croyden's Corner, New York Theater Wire, 2003 (Box 21)
    - Croyden's Corner, New York Theater Wire, 2004–2005 (Box 21)
    - Printed copies of theater reviews, 1997–2007; undated (Box 21)
    - Undated theater reviews (Box 21)
    - New York Theater Wire correspondence and miscelleaneous articles, 1997–2005 (Box 22)
    - Jerzy Grotowski related materials, 1969–2009 (Box 22)
    - Peter Brook related materials, 2001–2011 (Box 22)
    - Tom Stoppard related materials, 2002–2007 (Box 22)
    - Fordham Theater Institute and related materials, 1992–1999 (Box 22)
    - Wooster Group lawsuit related materials, 2004 (Box 22)
    - Panel work, 2003 (Box 22)
    - Miscelleanous theater related documents, 2003–2013 (Box 22)
    - A Christmas Story: The Musical script, 2012 November (Box 22)
    - Theater Week, 1989 November (Box 22)
    - Theater Week, 1990 January (Box 22)
    - Theater Week, 1990 August (Box 22)
    - Theater Week, 1991 (Box 23)
    - Theater Week, 1992 (Box 23)
    - Theater Week, 1993 (Box 23)
    - Theater Week, 1994 (Box 23)
    - Theater Week, 1995 (Box 23)
    - Theater Week, 1996 (Box 23)
    - American Theatre, 1990–1999 (Box 23)
    - American Theatre and AI (Performance for the Planet), 2001–2005 (Box 23)
  - School and Teaching Files, 1957-1991; Series IV; 1.25 linear feet (3 boxes)
    Series IV is arranged in loose groupings by format as recieved by the library.
    Series IV contains Croyden's notes from classes during her undergraduate career at Hunter College; teaching notes from her position as a professor of English literature at Jersey City State University; and students' papers.
    - Notes on W.B. Yeats, 1959 (Box 23)
    - Notes from Studies in Modern British and American Literature class, 1959 (Box 23)
    - Notes on Joseph Conrad, 1960 (Box 23)
    - Notes from English Social History class, 1959–1960 (Box 24)
    - Notes on Geoffrey Chaucer, 1960–1967 (Box 24)
    - Notes on Beowulf, 1960 (Box 24)
    - Notes from 18th century novel, English Poetry and English Drama, classes, 1963 (Box 24)
    - Various class notes and term papers, 1963-1966 (Box 24)
      This file includes notes and essays from the following classes: Comptemporary American and British Fiction, 1963; The Georgians and The Edwardians, 1965; Restoration Drama and Eighteenth Century Theatre, 1966; and The Age of Dryden and Pope, undated.
    - Hunter College documents and other school files, 1939–1964 (Box 24)
    - Graduation related materials, 1959–1961 (Box 24)
    - Notes from Modern Drama class, 1964 (Box 24)
    - Notes on Edwardians and Georgians, 1964- (Box 25)
    - Notes on Percy Bysshe Shelley, 1964–1976 (Box 25)
    - Notes on Anglo-Saxon literature, 1965–1966 (Box 25)
    - Notes on Honore de Balzac, 1966 (Box 25)
    - Notes on John Keats, 1966 (Box 25)
    - Notes from Greek Tragedy class, 1967 (Box 25)
    - Notes from Shakespeare class, 1972 (Box 25)
    - Notes on Williams Wordsworth, 1974 (Box 25)
    - Notes on English Drama, 1960 (Box 25)
    - Notes on Lord Byron, 1974–1976 (Box 25)
    - Notes from Shakespeare Tragedy and History class, 1979 (Box 25)
    - Notes on Anton Chekhov, 1975 (Box 25)
    - Notes on George Bernard Shaw, 1975 (Box 26)
    - Notes from Elizabethan Drama class, 1981 (Box 26)
    - Student term papers, 1991 (Box 26)
    - Notes from Elizabethan Poetry class, undated (Box 26)
    - Notes from Medieval and Renaissance literature class, undated (Box 26)
    - Notes from Shakespeare's theater class, undated (Box 26)
    - King Lear notes, undated (Box 26)
    - The Illiad notes, undated (Box 26)
    - Notes from Poetry class, undated (Box 26)
    - Notes from Romanticism class, undated (Box 26)
    - Notes from Modern British Literature course with focus on Thomas Hardy, undated (Box 26)
    - Notes from Contemporary Poetry class, undated (Box 26)
    - Notes from Contemporary Poetry and Literature class, undated (Box 26)
    - Notes on Nathaniel Hawthorne, undated (Box 26)
    - American literature notebooks, undated (Box 26)
    - American literature notes, undated (Box 26)
    - Notes on Herman Melville, 1964; undated (Box 27)
    - Notes from Victorian literature class, 1960 (Box 27)
    - Notes from Victorian literature class, undated (Box 27)
    - Notes on Thomas Carlyle, Robert Browning, etc., 1960–1962 (Box 27)
    - Oral Report on Franz Kafka for Croyden's class, undated (Box 27)
    - Notes from Modern Drama class, undated (Box 27)
    - Term papers written by Croyden, 1957–1963 (Box 27)
  - Travel Files, 1969-2006; Series V; 1.25 linear feet (3 boxes)
    Series V is arranged in loose groupings by format recieved by the library.
    Series V includes Croyden's travel journals, travel brochures, and tourist information. Also included are business cards and contact information for businesses and individuals from various cities.
    - Berlin travel information, 1969–1988; (2 folders) (Box 27)
    - Berlin brochures, 1970–1996; (4 folders) (Box 28)
    - Lebanon- Shiraz journal, 1973 (Box 28)
    - Lebanon brochures and travel documents, 1973; (2 folders) (Box 28)
    - American University of Beirut documents, 1973 (Box 28)
    - U.S.S.R. journal, 1973 (Box 28)
    - Moscow business cards and notes, undated (Box 28)
    - Israel journal, 1973 (Box 29)
    - Berlin notebook, business cards, and notes, 1975 (Box 29)
    - Milan notebook, 1979 (Box 29)
    - Florence, Bologna, and Rome business cards and notes, 2006; undated (Box 29)
    - Berlin, Budapest, and Prague notebook, 1990–1996 (Box 29)
    - Berlin, Budapest, and Prague notes and business cards, undated (Box 29)
    - Israel journal, 1999 (Box 29)
    - Vienna notes and business cards, 2000 (Box 29)
    - California notes, undated (Box 29)
    - Miscellaneous travel notes, undated (Box 29)
    - London travel notebook, undated (Box 29)
  - Posters and Photographs, 1968-1987; Series VI; 4.17 linear feet (2 boxes) + 1 broadside
    Series VI is arranged in loose groupings by format as recieved by the library.
    Series VI contains posters and photographs. The posters are from productions directed by Peter Brook and Jerzy Grotowski. The three photographs included are of Peter Brook, Jerzy Grotowski, and Margaret Croyden with an unidentified man.
    - Posters
      - Apocalypsis cum figuris, 1968 (Box 30 (broadside))
      - The Mahabaharata, 1987–1988 (Box 31 (oversize))
      - Conversations with Peter Brook, undated (Box 32 (oversize))
    - Photographs
      - Jerzy Grotowski, undated (Box 33)
      - Peter Brook, undated (Box 33)
      - Margaret Croyden and an unidentified man, undated (Box 33)
  - Restricted Fragile, 1975-2002; 1.59 linear feet (3 boxes)
    Boxes 34 and 36 (computer disks): Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    Box 35 (audiovisual material): Use of original is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Digital media (Box 34)
    - "Mother" - Lena Katz, age 85 (audiocassette), 1975 January 17; 1 (Box 35, Item barcode 39002104886966)
    - Laptop (Box 36 (oversize))
  - Restricted Papers, 0.21 linear feet (1 box) (Box 37)
    Box 37 contains papers that are restricted until 2066. For further information, please consult the appropriate curator.
    The box contains student papers graded by Croyden.